These date and time.
Item 2 of the public input and on schedule personal appearances and in the audience it was
just to address the council on any of the agenda items.
They're being non-added.
Three is consent agenda, staff is recommending items four through 11 for the consent agenda.
I don't think we're on that.
You're right.
MSUA.
We have a special initiative there.
Well, all of us.
I do have one.
So, I'm going to start over.
Forget everything I do say.
I'm going to call it older the Miami special utility authority meeting for today's date
and time.
Item 2 is the pledge of allegiance.
The forester.
The pledge of allegiance.
It's folded.
We're looking up.
Sorry it's long.
Thank you.
Brian.
Item 3.
Is public end put on schedule personal perdances.
Anyone else wish to address the authority to the Ab design?
ots want an EV agenda items.
There've been none.
Out of four is consent agenda.
Staff will determine what items 5 through 8 for the consent agenda.
There are no questions on any of those items.
Can your A flag orada agenda?
to the next. So we're going to strike item 8 from the consent agenda and then we'll take it
separately with the motion to table or there's no action. So the consent agenda revides
as item 5, 6 and 7. If there are no questions on you, those items are your time motion motion
to approve the consent agenda as recommended. I'll make the motion. And the second.
We'll call.
Question four, sir.
Louis, I'm working.
So.
Adam 8 is the whole harmless agreement with our vests and staff is asked that
item that there will be no action on that item that will be taken up at a later time.
Item 9 is the Department of I am a quality VQ permit. Well a number for replacement of water
lines on central avenue tile.
Yes, sir. So there's no action on this item. We'll proceed to acknowledge the permit.
I'm going to receive this VQ. So this is for the product we're doing on central and also
we know how we have our in-house created at the beforeing. So we're going to be doing from A to D street
and from 3rd to 4th. And I have been working.
Okay?
So there's no action like I said, it's just that we have to have a record and we have to
have a record.
Yes.
That's the key.
That's what's occurring over each other.
Any questions on out of nine before we move on?
Item 10 is to accept a redet change order.
Number one on the contract C18-110 with these contract construction.
For material substitution and additional unclassified excavation in the amount of
117-6750 on the central avenue product.
Yes.
So this is both on the city and they must do it.
So on the utility side, the contractor came back to us and said, I can go ahead and read
he bit an eight inch time piece that I can do at 12 inch length of the same price.
And it up to city out because obviously a lot of their fire flows.
You know, get better pressure to people in the area.
On the city side, on the work side on the street side, the unclassified excavation is also in their plan.
They forgot.
I did 11,000 millish worth of soil removal for the street.
So that's what that 11,000.
Okay.
So there's two amendments.
One is the contractor's going to give us a bigger pipe than he had originally bit at
No additional cost.
And the other amendment or change order is for excavation.
Yes.
Well, excavation.
What?
So unclassified excavation.
So you just think the soil underneath the road.
And it was just a line out of it that was left off of the original.
And there are quantities having creceptor contractor came back to him and said,
They think of the quantities for more than what they did.
Okay.
And this was a kind of track that there was some concern out because we were over budget, over the estimate.
And so this is going to be an additional amount over the estimate.
Yes, sir.
And how are we paying for this?
He's on his side.
He's on the other side.
And then I think that was made for the next generation.
Any questions for Tyler Kevin?
Okay.
Do we have a motion to?
Do we have a motion to accept change order number one?
Thank you.
And I'll second that roll call please.
Forster.
All right.
What's in?
Lewis.
Good.
Thanks Tyler.
I'm 11.
Except to reject also the Associates Work Order 18 slash 19.
Dash 8 for Street Improvement of West Central.
And mail an overlay of truth.
It's not to exceed $125,000.
Time is to borrow how it is.
Good.
So this is not a change order.
This is just there.
Is it a bid or an S.
Telling a bid for the doors.
to see the issue of project, the compassion test, the asphalt test, all that time of the work.
And right now, we have some of the projects to allow, we don't have a manpower, or the research.
Especially up to that, it's in the stuff too.
That's why we're recommending that folks have it all.
This is actually a work order for construction management on two projects.
It's a central project, and it's also the mill and all we're like project.
That gives us so many hours and side visits, frumbles, and to come and check quantities, they test the concrete, they test the asphalt, and they make sure everything is in compliance with the specs, but it's for the contractors.
Okay.
And this is a not too exceed, so if it's in fact, it needs more hours, you'll come back to the council and what you feel comfortable with the estimate.
You and Robert both feel comfortable with the estimate.
It's our first five-first street project of this size, so based on what the top of the Tyler talked to Shawn, this is a safe estimate.
Generally speaking, 10% is usually the estimate, or the standard, and I think this was actually a little lower anticipating.
Well, no better once we do the bit of it, especially for the mill and all over the world.
But the less central project, that's what it was million.
Correct.
So this is for the engineering and the oversight engineering, I'll call it, but we have an actually open the bids yet.
We have on the central project, we have not on the mill and all over the world.
Correct.
Any questions?
Money for this is also straight now.
It's budgeted and done.
This is a program for this.
We may comment in such a big project and we don't have the people, it's not that we're not doing an elsewhere.
This is just a such a big project.
Are we doing...
We're now seeing what else?
These are both contracted projects.
We're working on other end-kind projects, they're about to say it.
When we do the mill and overlay, all goes well with the bit of it, and we're going to be doing more than two miles and mill and overlay.
And that's why we wanted to have all some both from that power standpoint, and then also from a technical standpoint to make sure it's done properly and according to specs.
Again, what's central, that is all that's from Main Street and to the Main Street part of the memory.
And with these specs, I know that there's always a hot topic in the past.
These are correct.
I would just like to make sure whatever that is, we might be able to get an idea.
And we'll take that easy.
Sent to us on what inspectors can do this yet.
I also wrote the specs for the mill and overlay project, so that is out there.
You know, the mill and obviously, excuse me, for the central project.
And the mill and overlay is on ODOT's specs, and we can get those done.
It's very similar to the spec that we're used for a street, that'll last summer.
Thanks, Brian.
Okay, so do we have a motion to approve item 11?
I'll make a motion.
And we have a second.
Second.
Oh, hallways.
Louis, I, Weston, forster, orchid, shoulders.
Aye.
I'm 12.
Staff reports.
We're reporting your package available.
The staff has been a brilliant question on anything.
Item 13 is trust in community announcements.
Item 14 is adjourned.
We have a motion to adjourn the MSUA meeting.
It's motion.
Second.
Motion.
Fourth.